＜５年以下の懲役 または➡
50万円以下の
罰金に処せられます＞
＜後悔しても 元には戻せない＞
不正視聴!?
(サスケ)ぐっ… うっ…。
うっ！
ゲホッ ゲホッ ゲホッ！
うっ…。
Forgive me, Sasuke...
(イタチ)許せ サスケ。
これが オレの現実だ。
光をもらう。
This is my reality...
Give me your light.
ぐあぁ～!!
あぁ!! あっ… うわぁ～!!
うっ！ うっ…。
うっ…。
I told you.
だから言ったのだ。
万華鏡を持たないお前が➡
You do not possess
the Mangekyo Sharingan.
この眼を持つオレに
敵うはずがない と。
You can never win against
my eyes.
うっ！
もう片方も もらうぞ。
I’ll take the other one too.
くっ！
うっ…。
So that is the power of
the Curse Mark...
《あれが呪印の力か…》
This is the difference in
our strength.
これが 力の差だ。
そして➡
And...
お前と オレの瞳力の差だ。
the difference between
your ocular powers and mine.
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
《ゼツ : 案外 早かったね。
イタチの勝ちだ。
That was fast... Itachi’s won.
なぜだ？
How can you tell?
Sasuke’s caught in the Tsukuyomi.
だって 月読をくらったんだよ。
もう 動けやしないんだから。
He’s paralyzed. Itachi can do
whatever he wants now.
あとは 好きなように
料理できるでしょ》
《あれ？》
Huh?!
You broke through... my Tsukuyomi?!
お前… オレの月読を！
Huh? Sasuke took a Tsukuyomi,
so why isn’t he down?
《あれれ？ なんで サスケは 月読を
くらってるのに 倒れないんだ？
いや くらったんじゃない。
破ったんだ 月読を。
No... He didn’t fall for it.
He broke out of the Tsukuyomi.
What?! Someone with
an ordinary Sharingan could never win
えっ!? ただの写輪眼しか
持ってないヤツが➡
against the Mangekyo Sharingan!
万華鏡写輪眼に
勝てるはずがないだろ？
Even so, the Sharingan is
a ninja’s weapon.
写輪眼も忍の武器だ。
A weapon is only as powerful
as its wielder.
武器とは
それを扱う者の力量しだいで➡
It can be formidable or weak.
強くも弱くもなるもの。
You can have shuriken,
手裏剣を持っていても
達人の投げる小石に➡
and be taken down by
a mere pebble thrown by a master.
負けることだってある。
要は 力量の差…。
The difference is in the power.
サスケの才能が イタチの想像を
超えていたということだ》
It just means that Sasuke’s skills
far exceed Itachi’s expectations.
言ったはずだ。
Like I told you...
アンタが その眼を いくら使おうが➡
No matter how much you use
those eyes of yours,
このオレの憎しみで
幻は 現実になる と。
my hate will turn illusion into reality.
フッ… 幻は現実になる か。
Humph... Make illusions a reality, eh?
それこそ そのセリフ
そのまま 返しておこう。
Then let me throw those words
right back at you.
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
Like I told you...
言ったはずだ。
No matter how much you use
those eyes of yours,
アンタが その眼を いくら使おうが➡
my hate will turn illusion into reality.
このオレの憎しみで
幻は 現実になる と。
Humph... Make illusions a reality, eh?
フッ… 幻は現実になる か。
それこそ そのセリフ
そのまま 返しておこう。
Then let me throw those words
right back at you.
Amaterasu
You saw your eyes gouged out
during the Tsukuyomi just now.
さっきの月読で 己の眼がもがれる
幻は見ただろう。
ならば それを現実にしてやる。
Well, allow me to make that a reality.
The air around Itachi has shifted!
《あっ！
イタチの醸す空気が変わった。
He’s gotten serious.
本気になったようだ。
Which means,
we might get to see the Amaterasu.
これなら あの天照が
見られるかもしれんぞ。
What? The Amaterasu?!
I can’t wait to see it!
えっ!? 天照を？
そりゃ 楽しみだ。
We were right to come see this,
after all!
やっぱ
こっち 見にきて 正解だった》
Continuing to use genjutsu
will lead nowhere.
《幻術同士では
らちがあかない。
Now that Sasuke has broken
the Tsukuyomi,
サスケが 月読を破った時点で
もう 幻術戦は無意味だ。
a genjutsu battle is pointless.
Which means from now on,
it’ll be ninjutsu against ninjutsu.
じゃあ ここからは 直接
忍術のぶつかり合いってことだね。
If Itachi’s left Mangekyo possesses
the ultimate genjutsu,
イタチの左の万華鏡が
最強の幻術を持つなら➡
then his right Mangekyo is
the ultimate in physical attacks.
右の万華鏡は最強の物理攻撃…。
The Amaterasu produces black flames
that are said to never extinguish...
天照は その眼が映したものを
焼き尽くすまで消えない➡
Not until it incinerates the target
within the caster’s sight.
黒い炎といわれる》
Is this it, the Amaterasu?!
《出るか!? 天照！
How quick... He’s planning to
not let Itachi weave signs!
速い！ 印を結ばせない気だ》
This is the Shadow Shuriken Jutsu!
《これは 影手裏剣の術》
《仕込み手裏剣!?》
A rigged shuriken?!
《フッ… 最後の手裏剣で
うまくいったな》
That last shuriken did the job.
《おかしい。
That’s strange...
どうしたの？
What is it?
It’s just that Itachi should have been
able to dodge something like that.
いや あんなものを避けきれない
イタチでは ないはずだが…》
Backlash from that earlier Tsukuyomi?
さっきの月読の反動か？
フッ… いい感じだな おい！
I like that.
From the moment
Sasuke nullified the Tsukuyomi,
《月読をしのいだ時点で➡
he seized control of the flow
of the battle.
サスケが戦いの流れをつかんでるね。
Plus he slowed down
Itachi’s movements.
さらにイタチの動きも鈍らせたし➡
Sasuke might actually win this battle.
この勝負 サスケが勝っちまうかもよ。
いや それは まだわからんぞ》
No... We don’t know that yet.
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
火遁 豪火球の術！
くっ！
Wounds like this won’t slow me down.
《この程度の傷じゃ まだまだだ》
Phew... We almost got caught in that!
ふぅ～ 巻き添えを
食うとこだった。
– Fire Style! Fireball Jutsu!
《２人 : 火遁 豪火球！》
ん？
Sasuke has the upper hand.
《サスケのほうがおしてる…。
I really think Sasuke’s going to...
この戦い やっぱりサスケの…》
Amaterasu!
《天照！》
Ohh... There it is!
《おぉ！ 出た！》
《す すげえ！
炎で炎を食い尽くした》
I-Incredible...
He put out fire with fire.
あの術は
燃やしたいところを目視し➡
With that jutsu,
he eyes whatever he wants to burn
ピントが合うだけで
その視点から黒炎が発生する。
and once the target is in focus,
black flames burst forth.
黒炎は捉えたものを
燃やし尽くすまで消えない。
The black flame cannot
be extinguished
until the one it targets
is totally incinerated.
その対象が炎であってもだ。
Even if the target is also fire.
あ～っ！
《やっぱりイタチの勝ちか。
I guess Itachi is the winner, after all.
天照を止めたな。
He stopped the Amaterasu...
He’s going to take Sasuke’s eyes.
眼を奪う気だ》
うん？ 下に？
Huh?
He went below?!
《この程度の傷じゃ まだまだだ。
Wounds like this won’t
slow me down.
ヤツが天照を出すまでは
この変わり身の術は使えない》
I can’t use this Substitution Jutsu
until he unleashes his Amaterasu.
《これを待ってたんだ！》
This is what I’ve been waiting for!
うん？
火遁 豪龍火の術！
Huh?
Fire Style: Fire Jutsu!
《お～っ やるねえ！
Hey, pretty good.
マズイ…》
Oh no!
さっきの天照…
相当の負担がかかったようだな。
That Amaterasu earlier seems to have
taken quite a toll on you.
《もう ２人とも バテバテだね。
チャクラないんじゃない？
They’re both totally exhausted.
They have no chakra left, huh?
そのようだな…》
So it appears.
これが…
オレの最後の術になるだろう。
This will probably be my last jutsu.
フッ…。
写輪眼は チャクラを見る眼だ。
The Sharingan can assess chakra.
強がりはよせ。 もう お前に
チャクラが残っていないのは わかる。
Stop bluffing...
I can see that you’re out of chakra.
天照を回避した
大蛇丸流の変わり身の術。
You evaded my Amaterasu
using the Orochimaru-style
Substitution Jutsu.
バレにくく よくできた変わり身だが
あれは 多量のチャクラを使う。
A well-made substitution to deceive,
but it uses an enormous amount
of chakra.
《そうか… サスケは
大蛇丸を取り込んだから！
That’s right...
Sasuke did absorb Orochimaru!
そういうことか…》
So that’s it.
たしかに
今のオレには チャクラはない。
You’re right.
I don’t have any chakra left.
さっきの火遁で
すべてを使い切ったからな。
I used it up in that
last Fire Style Jutsu.
だが… アンタを殺すのに➡
However...
Do you really think I would
come here to kill you unprepared?
オレが 何もせず
ここに来たと思うか？
一瞬だ。 この術は 天照と同じだ。
It will be instantaneous.
This jutsu is just like Amaterasu.
絶対に かわすことはできない。
It is impossible to dodge.
さて… ご希望どおり 再現しよう。
Now...
As you wished, I’ll recreate...
アンタの死に様を…。
your death!
you are next to me
omae ga tonari ni iru
you are laughing
omae ga waratte iru
you seem so happy
omae ga ureshisou de
so I laughed too
ore mo waratta
you were so innocent and naive
omae wa mujaki datta
you were so kindhearted
omae wa yasashi katta
you sometimes cried
omae wa tokidoki naki
so I was troubled
ore wa komatta
who did I ask strength from at that time
dare yori tsuyosa wo motometa ano koro
since that was my one and only weakness
ore no tatta hitotsu no yowasa ga
that was you
omae datta
and it was you
omae datta n da
I want to see you
aitai
overnights
yoru wo koete
over time
toki wo koete
I want to see you now
ima aitai
Next Episode
Oh wow...
I’m glad we chose to see this once.
(シズネ)ひぃ～っ！ まったく
なんで こんなに➡
I never thought we could see
such a battle.
ためこんじゃうんですか！
(綱手)すまないねぇ。
Sasuke’s jutsu was impressive,
ん？ ナルト君の登録番号って
いくつでしたっけ？
but to think Itachi was hiding
that kind of jutsu up his sleeve.
そんなことも わからないのか。
ナルトは 012607。
But looks like it also comes
with a heavy risk...
じゃあ サクラの任務経験は？
Who will win this battle...?
Ｃランクが９回 Ｂランクが６回
Ａランクが７回。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: “The End”
なら サイ君の身長と体重は？
172センチ 53キロ。
Either way,
the next one will be their last.
The End
ヤマト隊長のお誕生日は？
８月10日。
Seriously! Why do you pile up
this much work?!
紅先生の趣味は？
ハッハッハッハ！
晩酌だよ！ 晩酌！
Sorry.
What was Naruto-kun’s registration number?
さすが 綱手様。 なんでも
把握してらっしゃるんですね。
You don’t even know that?
Naruto is #012607.
それに比べて 私ったら…。
当たり前だろう。 私は 火影だぞ。
Then how many missions
did Sakura carry out?
(シズネ)そうですよね。
比べた私が バカでした。
Nine C-rank, six B-rank,
and seven A-rank missions.
あ… ところで 綱手様の
賭け事以外のご趣味は？
Then what is Sai’s height and weight?
172 cm, 53 kg.
《しまった！ 書いてない！》
(シズネ)あ… 大丈夫ですよ！
いくら 火影様であろうと➡
Captain Yamato’s birthday?!
August 10th.
What is Kurenai-sensei’s hobby?!
寄る年波には 勝てぬ… ひゃっ！
Drinking! She enjoys evening drinks!
You’re amazing, Tsunade-sama.
You’re aware of everything.
(ナツ)すぐ近くに仲間がいるんだ。
Me, on the other hand...
今は 恐れることはねえ！
Naturally. I am the Hokage!
俺たちは １人じゃねえんだ！
"THE OFFICIAL SHIPPUDEN HANDBOOK"
You’re right. How foolish to
even compare myself to you.
Oh, by the way...
What is your hobby besides gambling?
Oh no... It’s not listed in here!
(ハデス)すべてを闇の底へ！
D-Don’t worry about it!
日が沈むときだ フェアリーテイル！
After all,
even a Hokage can’t beat old age--!